[POLICEMAN 19D]
No! Wait! I did as you said!
I killed the criminal
who went after Whiteley!
What more do you want?
Please, spare me!
[HARRY]
Very good.
As per Mister
Milverton's instructions,
we're to make sure that this
officer's body is never found.
Dump him somewhere suitable.
As for our next target...
Heh. The MP's brother,
little Sam Whiteley.
[SAM]
What's wrong, Adam?
That's quite the
expression you're wearing.
Something's on
your mind, isn't it?
Yes, a small matter.
But there's no need
to worry, Sam.
Things are going to take
a turn for the better.
Right.
[MAGGIE]
Excuse me, sir.
Chief Inspector Paterson
is here to see you.
[WHITELEY]
All right, I'll be right there.
[SAM] You mean the
world to me brother.
I only wish I could
always be by your side.
[PATERSON]
A few hours ago,
a police officer named
Bartholomew Fowler
was found murdered in
one of the city's slums.
The troubling part
is Officer Fowler was a guard
in the Yard's detention block.
The night the bomber was killed,
he was the officer on duty.
Per our investigation,
we've discovered Officer Fowler
has a gravely ill mother.
A great deal of money was
required for her care.
Then, two days ago,
he settled with the
hospital in one lump sum.
They got to him by exploiting
the condition of his mother.
Fiends.
So the bomber
was hired to kill me.
Fowler was hired to silence him,
then was silenced himself.
I must also remark.
This extortion and murder
are unlike any of
our previous cases.
This was clearly the
work of a professional.
Listen, please do take
care to be more wary.
We're dealing with
dangerous people.
[WHITELEY]
I understand.
Marcus, kindly cancel
my entire morning schedule.
There's somewhere that
I need to go alone instead.
[MARCUS grunts]
[WHITELEY] Inspector Robinson,
Inspector Sturridge.
I want you to remain
at the residence,
and keep everyone here safe.
After everything
that has happened,
it's simply out of the question!
You heard what the chief
inspector just told you!
Sir, please listen to reason!
I'll be back shortly.
You needn't worry.
But, sir!
He's going to
negotiate by himself.
Awfully bold of him.
[WHITELEY grunts]
Hello there.
My name is Charles
Augustus Milverton.
The House of Lords
requested I act
as their representative.
[MILVERTON] Do you take
any exception to this?
[BONDE]
That's Milverton!
What's he doing here?
I have to let Will
know about this!
No.
Who better to represent them,
than a figure of your
stature and influence.
How kind.
Now, to the matter at hand.
Interesting.
And what do you
intend to do with this?
You'll find my demands
to be rather simple.
For my first concern,
there is a bill I'm pushing
through the House of Commons.
Expanding the vote.
If the House of Lords
fights it, I will go public.
Is that all?
[WHITELEY]
I was getting to that.
No harm will be
visited upon myself,
or any of my family and friends.
Or I swear, I will
go public with this.
But as long as both of
those conditions are met,
I'll bite my tongue.
[MILVERTON]
Hmm.
Very well.
I'll relay both of your
demands to my clients
exactly as you've described.
[WHITELEY] The best
defence is a good offence.
Finally, the path to an ideal
society is all but guaranteed.
[MILVERTON chuckles]
What a farce.
Imagine, me, the king of
blackmailers, being blackmailed.
But unfortunately for him,
I don't back
down under extortion.
[FRED]
What? Someone broke in?
That's impossible!
[GOSLING grunts]
[gasps]
[HARRY] Sorry to barge in
when you're in such a rush.
But if you interfere now,
you'll ruin the show
we have all planned out.
We wouldn't want that.
You get to play with us, Fred.
[SAM]
Maggie! Maggie?
I could use your
help with something.
[SAM sighs]
[SAM]
What's the matter? Maggie?
- -[thud]
- -[SAM gasps, groans]
No! Maggie!
[gasps] Oh, my God.
[SAM groans]
Thank goodness you're here!
Get a doctor!
Maggie's been--
[SAM gasps]
[thunder rumbles]
[door opens]
[WHITELEY]
Maggie, I made it back.
Hello?
[WHITELEY]
Marcus? Marcus!
What the devil's going on here?
[gasps]
[WHITELEY]
This can't be happening!
No! Samuel!
Please, Maggie!
Someone, answer me!
[WHITELEY]
Wh-What have they done to you?
[gasps]
[WHITELEY]
Sam.
[WHITELEY whimpers]
[screams, sobs]
[WHITELEY]
Oh, Sam.
No. Not you.
Why...?
Why? [sobs]
[WHITELEY]
Who's there?
[gasps]
[WHITELEY]
Inspector Sturridge.
Who did this to them?
Why are you the only
one who wasn't killed?
[WHITELEY gasps]
Don't tell me...
[MILVERTON]
The age old question,
why do devils tempt men
to try and sully
their hands with evil?
The answer is remarkably simple.
For a devil compelling
those who do good deeds
to commit despicable acts,
well, there is no
greater pleasure.
Since the dawn of time,
nothing has held more allure
for mankind than wrongdoing.
Consequently, it is depicted
in the Bible as a sin--
a forbidden delight.
The true essence of evil
is the pursuit thereof.
When pure, it transcends
the rigors and morals
established by man.
The Lord of Crime's
sins are banal,
merely based on
societal conventions.
Whereas, I, on the other hand--
I am "evil" incarnate.
[WHITELEY]
You're responsible for this?
That's right. It was by my hand.
I killed them,
every member of your family.
[WHITELEY] And you're just
matter-of-factly telling me?
How could you?!
Sam was-- He was nothing
but a defenceless boy.
What reason could
you possibly have?
Why? Why him?
And then you come forward
confessing your sins?
As if you were
seeking absolution?
I have no illusions
about you forgiving me.
However, please believe this.
What I did-- I never wanted
to commit such atrocities.
I don't want to hear
any lies, Sturridge!
I swear, it isn't a lie!
I was forced to under duress!
Explain right now.
I don't know who, but someone
took my wife and child,
only leaving behind a threat.
It read "Kill every member
of Whiteley's family.
Then confess what
you've done to him.
Do this and I will return
your wife and child."
[STURRIDGE]
I don't care what happens to me,
as long as my family is safe.
[STURRIDGE]
I killed them with this knife.
Use it. Deliver justice.
[gasps]
[WHITELEY]
This is the man who killed
Sam and Maggie and Marcus.
[grunting]
[WHITELEY growls]
[WHITELEY]
Sam.
Without you in my life,
there's no reason to change the
world, or for me to live in it.
[yells]
[WHITELEY]
Damn! Damn! Damn!
[WHITELEY] I just-- I just
can't bring myself to kill him.
[groans]
[MILVERTON chuckling]
There is no more
satisfactory delight imaginable.
Whiteley, a politician widely
regarded as a hero, uncorrupted,
has just stained his hands
the darkest shade of red.
Yes, exactly as I had intended.
[MILVERTON] And with that,
a new villain emerges.
[clang]
[HARRY laughs] Gotta say,
you're doing remarkably well
for being outnumbered.
I'm beginning to get
invested in this fight.
Sadly, we've got quite
the busy schedule.
Sorry, Fred. Time's up.
Now, you die.
[grunts]
Louis!
I'll handle them! Stay back!
[GOSLING grunts]
I have a message from my boss.
He says, "Let us have a nice
chat about the future sometime,
whilst gazing out over the sea."
You get all that?
We'll continue this later.
I bid you farewell... for now.
[ALBERT]
Mister Whiteley.
[WHITELEY]
Thank you for meeting me here.
I apologize for the hour,
Lord Moriarty.
I thought it'd be best
if I returned the evidence
considering it won't be
of use to me any longer.
I see. And why would that be?
Please keep your composure
when I tell you this,
but earlier tonight,
I killed a man
with my own hands.
My family was slain by
the officer I trusted.
I stabbed him.
I couldn't help myself!
Reasons notwithstanding,
the fact is I took
another man's life.
And a police officer, at that...
I'll be fair game for
my political rivals.
Never mind passing my bill,
the path to bringing
equality to this nation
is completely cut off now.
If only there was a way
I could atone with my own life.
[WILLIAM]
Indeed.
[WHITELEY grunts]
Who are you?
I am Albert's younger brother.
You can call me William.
Younger brother? I didn't
realize that he had one.
Thank you for confessing
despite the deep
grief you're in.
The fact is, you've been setup
by someone, Mister Whiteley.
This individual,
they are attempting to thwart
all efforts of equality
by driving its most vocal
advocate to commit murder.
And you did.
Their manipulations
proved successful.
[WHITELEY] Hmph. That's
one way of putting it.
But I'm afraid the
decision to lower myself
and commit murder
was mine alone.
I killed all chances
of reforming Britain.
[WILLIAM]
It's not over just yet.
[WHITELEY grunts]
Sir, if you're truly sincere,
and you intend to atone for
your crime with your death...
...then allow me
to make a request.
Hand your life over to me.
[REPORTERS murmuring]
Seems like there's
a storm brewing.
Just what we need before both
Houses are ready to convene.
I wonder if Whiteley
is really coming after all.
From what I heard, his family
and bodyguards were murdered.
Aye, and even worse than that,
the culprit is still at large.
Look, there he is!
[POLICEMAN 20A]
Everyone, please keep back!
We don't want
anyone in harm's way.
You there, keep back!
[REPORTER 20A]
Sir! Mister Whiteley!
Can you describe what you're
going through right now?
[REPORTER 20B] Mister Whiteley!
Your thoughts, please.
I've lost them.
My precious family's gone.
They were murdered
in cold blood,
along with the officers
who were protecting me.
However, I will by no
means take a step back.
You all have my word.
I'll continue fighting
to end inequality.
I won't stop.
No matter if even greater
adversities lie ahead for me.
I won't succumb to fear!
[REPORTERS cheering]
[REPORTERS]
Whiteley! Whiteley! Whiteley!
[REPORTER 20A]
Mister Whiteley!
You truly are this
country's white knight!
[REPORTERS]
Whiteley!
[thud]
[REPORTERS gasp]
[REPORTER 20B]
Whiteley! He's been stabbed!
Who the devil is that man?
[WILLIAM]
You haven't guessed yet?
I killed the MP's family and the
two inspectors guarding them.
This entire series of
events was orchestrated
and carried out by me,
the Lord of Crime!
Him? He's the one responsible?
It's really him!
I didn't think the
Lord of Crime was real.
Oh, I'm real, and I will
cast all of London society
into the fiery depths of Hell.
That is, unless there's
someone in this city
who has what it
takes to stop me!
[REPORTERS gasp]
Seize him! Don't let him go!
We caught him red-handed!
[POLICEMEN]
Sir!
Apprehend the Lord of Crime!
Hold on, sir! We'll get help!
Someone! Fetch a doctor! Hurry!
[WHITELEY] Give my life
to you? How will that help?
[WILLIAM] The class system
is strangling this country.
The people can't
afford to lose hope now,
and if your crime
ever comes to light,
then all of their dreams
will turn to despair.
And there will be no
chance at equality.
I agree!
But even if I die, it still
won't help to erase my crime!
That's our burden to carry now.
Your crime will become ours.
How can that be?
All I ask is that you die
playing the part of
this country's saviour.
You may consider the performance
to be your final act of penance.
But why? I'm the guilty one!
So why willingly
take the blame for it
and volunteer to
play the villain?
[WILLIAM]
Because...
...that is the role
the Lord of Crime
was always meant to play.
[POLICEMAN 20B]
There he is!
On the roof! Head him off!
[POLICEMEN shout]
Move it! Don't let
the fiend get away!
And cordon off the area!
You've gotta stay
with us, sir! Hold on!
[WHITELEY]
Moriarty.
Without hesitation,
you chose to be
a necessary evil,
the sort this society
desperately needs.
I am sure that you
and your brothers
will be able to bring
change to this nation.
There you are!
[WHITELEY] I leave this land's
fate to you, Lord of Crime.
[WILLIAM]
Which will come out on top?
Necessary evil or pure evil?
In the end only one will
remain. Right, Milverton?
[WATSON] Next time
on Moriarty the Patriot  :
"The Sign of Mary."